Guide to the Herbert Aptheker Papers, 1842-1999, (bulk 1934-1994)
Department of Special Collections
- Series 2. Aptheker Articles, Manuscripts, and Notes
  - Chile symposium [2 of 2], 1973 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Mahn- und Gedenkstotten in der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik: portfolio, 1964 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - Sozialistische Einheitspartei Deutschlands: portfolio, 1966 June 29 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Aptheker biography, n.d., ams (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - Aptheker biography, Vol. II, n.d., ams (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - Aptheker manuscripts: The American Civil War (1861-1865), 1954 (Box 190, Folder 3)
  - Important papers & speeches, 1960 - 1969 (Box 190, Folder 4)
  - Important papers & speeches: Academic freedom in the United States, 1960 - 1969 (Box 190, Folder 5)
  - Important papers & speeches: Some unpublished writing of W.E.B. Du Bois / ed. by Herbert Aptheker, 1964 - 1965 (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence on University of Massachusetts, 1970 - 1986 (Box 190, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Affairs essays and Du Bois on religion, 1970-1984 (Box 190, Folder 8)
  - Important papers & speeches: review of Wagandt's The might revolution (Box 190, Folder 9)
  - Important papers & speeches: Alienation & the American social order (Box 190, Folder 10)
  - Important papers & speeches: Review of The abolitionists (Box 190, Folder 11)
  - Important papers & speeches: Review of Nazi propoganda (Box 190, Folder 12)
  - Important papers & speeches: Review of Werth's Russia at war (Box 190, Folder 13)
  - Important papers & speeches: Du Bois on Florence Kelley (Box 190, Folder 14)
  - Important papers & speeches: Du Bois on James Weldon Johnson (Box 190, Folder 15)
  - Herbert Aptheker misc. articles, manuscripts, notes, 1950 - 1959 (Box 190, Folder 16)
  - Herbert Aptheker misc. articles, manuscripts, notes, 1950 - 1959 (Box 190, Folder 17)
  - Herbert Aptheker misc. articles, manuscripts, notes, including court cases, 1954 (Box 190, Folder 18)
  - Herbert Aptheker misc. articles, manuscripts, notes on McCarthyism, 1955 (Box 190, Folder 19)
  - Herbert Aptheker misc. articles, manuscripts, notes, 1960 - 1969 (Box 190, Folder 20)
  - Aptheker, Herbert. Notes for W.E. Burghardt Du Bois' Dusk of Dawn, n.d., ams (6 p.). Very fragile (Box 190, Folder 21)
  - Valentine, Charles & Bettylon. Brain damage and the intellectual defense of inequality. -- In Current Anthropology. -- Vol. 16, no. 1, 1975 Mar. (Box 190, Folder 22)
    Includes printed comments by Herbert Aptheker.
  - Barnes & Noble welcomes Herbert Aptheker, author of A documentary history of the Negro people in the United States, to a reading & discussion, Friday, Oct. 21st., 7 p.m.: poster,, 1994, 1 item; 73 x 56 cm.
    [Note: item requires conservation treatment and may be temporarily unavailable during treatment.]
  - Mississippi showing White and Black population of the counties in 1870, 1 l.; 35 x 25 cm. Extremely fragile; enclosed in mylar.
  - The American Negro: scrapbook, 1 v. (Box 193)
- Series 3. Printed Materials
  Contains books, serials with which Aptheker was involved, articles by others, and historically valuable pamphlets used by Aptheker in his research.
  - Subseries A. Books
    - Shapiro, Herbert, ed. African American history & radical historiography: essays in honor of Herbert Aptheker. -- Minneapolis: MEP Publications, 1998 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Subseries B. Serials
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 1-13, 1964 - 1976, 1 v. (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 4, 1967 (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 5, 1968 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 6, 1969 (Box 135, Folder 5)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 7, 1970 (Box 135, Folder 6)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 8, 1971 (Box 135, Folder 7)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 9, 1972 (Box 135, Folder 8)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 10, 1973 (Box 135, Folder 9)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 11, 1974 (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 12, 1975 (Box 135, Folder 11)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 13, 1976 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 14, 1977 (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 15, 1978 (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 16, 1979 (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 17, 1980 (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 18, 1981 (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 19, 1982 (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 20, 1983 (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 21, 1984 (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - AIMS newsletter. -- Vol. 22, 1985 (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 11, no. 1, 1971 (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 11, no. 2, 1971 (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 11, no. 3, 1971 (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 11, no. 4, 1971 (Box 136, Folder 14)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 12, no. 1, 1972 (Box 136, Folder 15)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 12, no. 2, 1972 (Box 136, Folder 16)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 12, no. 3, 1972 (Box 136, Folder 17)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 12, no. 4, 1972 (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 13, no. 1, 1973 (Box 137, Folder 2)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 13, no. 2, 1973 (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 13, no. 3, 1973 (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 13, no. 4, 1973 (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 14, no. 1, 1974 (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 14, no. 2, 1974 (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 14, no. 3, 1974 (Box 137, Folder 8)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 14, no. 4, 1974 (Box 137, Folder 9)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 15, no. 1, 1975 (Box 137, Folder 10)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 15, no. 2, 1975 (Box 137, Folder 11)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 15, no. 3, 1975 (Box 137, Folder 12)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 15, no. 4, 1975 (Box 137, Folder 13)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 16, no. 1, 1976 (Box 137, Folder 14)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 16, no. 2, 1976 (Box 137, Folder 15)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 16, no. 3, 1976 (Box 137, Folder 16)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 16, no. 4, 1976 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 17, no. 1, 1977 (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 17, no. 2, 1977 (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 17, no. 3, 1977 (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 17, no. 4, 1977 (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 18, no. 1, 1978 (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 18, no. 2, 1978 (Box 138, Folder 7)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 18, no. 3, 1978 (Box 138, Folder 8)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 18, no. 4, 1978 (Box 138, Folder 9)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 19, no. 1, 1979 (Box 138, Folder 10)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 19, no. 2, 1979 (Box 138, Folder 11)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 19, no. 3, 1979 (Box 138, Folder 12)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 19, no. 4, 1979 (Box 138, Folder 13)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 20, no. 2, 1980 (Box 138, Folder 14)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 20, no. 3, 1980 (Box 138, Folder 15)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 21, no. 1, 1981 (Box 138, Folder 16)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 21, no. 2, 1981 (Box 138, Folder 17)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 21, no. 3, 1981 (Box 138, Folder 18)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 22, no. 1, 1982 (Box 139, Folder 1)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 22, no. 2, 1982 (Box 139, Folder 2)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 22, no. 3, 1982 (Box 139, Folder 3)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 22, no. 4, 1982 (Box 139, Folder 4)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 23, no. 1, 1983 (Box 139, Folder 5)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 23, no. 2, 1983 (Box 139, Folder 6)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 23, no. 3, 1983 (Box 139, Folder 7)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 24, no. 1, 1984 (Box 139, Folder 8)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 24, no. 2, 1984 (Box 139, Folder 9)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 24, no. 3, 1984 (Box 139, Folder 10)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 24, no. 4, 1984 (Box 139, Folder 11)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 25, no. 1, 1985 (Box 139, Folder 12)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 25, no. 2, 1985 (Box 139, Folder 13)
    - Freedomways. -- Vol. 25, no. 3, 1985 (Box 139, Folder 14)
    - AIMS Newsletter. -- Vol. 1, 1964 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - AIMS Newsletter. -- Vol. 2, 1965 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - AIMS Newsletter. -- Vol. 3, 1966 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - AIMS Newsletter. -- Vol. 4, 1967 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - Southern Patriot. -- Vol. 3, nos. 1-12, 1945 (Box 140, Folder 5)
    - Southern Patriot. -- Vol. 4, nos. 1-11, 1946 (Box 140, Folder 6)
    - Southern Patriot. -- Vol. 5, nos. 1, 2, 8; vol. 8, 1947, 1950 (Box 140, Folder 7)
  - Subseries C. Articles
    - Graham, Frank P. The meaning of the Civil War. -- In Virginia Quarterly Review. -- Vol. 38, 1962 Winter (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Cochran, Thomas C. Did the Civil War retard industrialization? -- In MVHR. -- Vol. 48, 1961 Sept. (Box 141, Folder 2)
    - Owsley, Harriet Chappell. Henry Shelton Sanford and federal surveillance abroad, 1861-1865. -- In MHVR. -- Vol. 48, 1961 Sept. (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - Hammond, Bray. The North's empty purse, 1861-1862. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 67, no. 1, 1961 Oct. (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Lemisch, L. Jesse. Who won the Civil War, anyway? -- In The Nation., 1961 Apr. 8 (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Rayback, Robert J. New York State in the Civil War. -- In New York History. -- Vol. 42, 1961 Jan. (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Snyder, Charles. Oswego County's response to the Civil War. -- In New York History., 1961 Jan. (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Whitridge, Arnold. Fanaticism--North and South. -- In Virginia Quarterly Review., 1962 Summer (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Shryock, Richard. A medical perspective on the Civil War. -- In American Quarterly. -- Vol. 14, 1962 Summer (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - The Civil War branch library book news. -- New York Public Library., 1961 Apr. (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Williams, T. Harry. Testing whether any nation so conceived and so dedicated could long endure. -- In New York Book Review., 1959 Jan. 18 (Box 141, Folder 11)
    - Linneman, William R. Southern Punch: a draught of Confederate wit. -- In Southern Folklore Quarterly. -- Vol. 26, no. 2, 1962 June (Box 141, Folder 12)
    - Lawrence, David. Does might make right? -- In U. S. News & World Report., 1961 Apr. 17 (Box 141, Folder 13)
    - Bernstein, Samuel. The oppoition of French labor to American slavery. -- In Science & Society., 1953 Spring (Box 141, Folder 14)
    - Luthin, Reinhard H. Fakes and frauds in Lincoln literature. -- In Saturday Review., 1959 Feb. 14 (Box 141, Folder 15)
    - Williams, William Appleman. Review of Lincoln and the Russians. -- In Science & Society., 1953 Fall (Box 141, Folder 16)
    - Norton, Lee. War elections, 1862-1864. -- New York: International Publishers., n.d. (Box 141, Folder 17)
    - Mandel, Bernard. Calhoun, Lincoln, and labor. -- In Science & Society., 1954 Summer (Box 141, Folder 18)
    - Branch library book news. -- Vol. 38, no. 4, 1961 Apr. (Box 141, Folder 19)
    - Aptheker, Herbert. The American Civil War: a centenary article. -- In Mainstream., 1961 Feb. (Box 141, Folder 20)
    - Fishwick, Marshall. Robert E. Lee: the guardian angel myth. -- In Saturday Review., 1961 Mar. 4 (Box 141, Folder 21)
    - Kazin, Alfred. A city of the soul. -- In The Reporter., 1961 June 8 (Box 141, Folder 22)
    - Centenary of the birth of the Confederacy., 1961 (Box 141, Folder 23)
    - Sinkler, George. Benjamin Harrison and the matter of race. -- In Indiana Magazine of History. -- Vol. 65, no. 3, 1969 Sept. (Box 141, Folder 24)
    - Centennial Review Civil War issue. -- Vol. 5, no. 1, 1961 Winter (Box 141, Folder 25)
    - Civil War clippings., n.d. (Box 141, Folder 26)
    - Eaton, Clement. A strange war to modern eyes. -- In Virginia Quarterly Review., 1959 Winter (Box 141, Folder 27)
    - Brogan, D. W. A fresh appraisal of the Civil War. -- In Harper's., 1960 Apr. (Box 141, Folder 28)
    - Adams, Francis R. Robert E. Lee & the concept of democracy. -- In American Quarterly., 1960 Fall (Box 141, Folder 29)
    - Notes & book reviews., n.d. (Box 141, Folder 30)
    - Woodward, C. Vann. Equality: America's deferred commitment. -- In American Scholar., 1958 Autumn (Box 141, Folder 31)
    - Robinson, William M. Review of Opinions of the Confederate Attorneys General. -- In AHR., 1950 Oct. (Box 141, Folder 32)
    - Civil War clippings., n.d. (Box 141, Folder 33)
    - Schappes, Morris U. Civil War centennial: celebration or desecration? -- In Jewish Currents., 1961 Jan. (Box 141, Folder 34)
    - Notes on Civil War centennial., n.d. (Box 141, Folder 35)
    - Harlan, Louis R. Booker T. Washington in biographical perspective. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 75, no. 6, 1970 Oct. (Box 141, Folder 36)
    - Walden, Daniel. Race and imperialism: the Achilles heel of the Progressives. -- In Science & Society., 1967 Spring (Box 141, Folder 37)
    - Roske, Ralph J. The seven martyrs? -- In American Historical Review., 1959 Jan. (Box 141, Folder 38)
    - Riddleberger, Patrick W. The Republican Party and the Southern Negro, 1877-1897. -- In Journal of Negro History. -- Vol. 45, no. 2, 1960 Apr. (Box 141, Folder 39)
    - Kelly, Alfred H. The congressional controversy over school segregation, 1867-1875. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 64, no. 3, 1959 Apr. (Box 141, Folder 40)
    - Hyman, Harold M. Johnson, Stanton, and Grant: a reconsideration of the Army's role in the events leading to impeachment., n.d. (Box 141, Folder 41)
    - Kirkland, Edward C. The Robber Barons revisited. -- In AHR., 1960 Oct. (Box 141, Folder 42)
    - Bernstein, Samuel. Wendell Phillips: labor advocate. -- In Science & Society., 1956 Fall (Box 141, Folder 43)
    - Lawson, Elizabeth. The gentleman from Mississippi: our first Negro Senator [Hiram R. Revels]. -- New York: Author., 1960 (Box 141, Folder 44)
    - Williams, T. Harry. An analysis of some reconstruction attitudes. -- In Journal of Southern History. -- Vol. 12, no. 4, 1946 Nov. (Box 141, Folder 45)
    - Civil War clippings., n.d. (Box 141, Folder 46)
    - Hirsch, Mark D. Samuel J. Tilden: the story of a lost opportunity. -- In AHR. -- Vol. 56, 1951 July (Box 141, Folder 47)
    - Taylor, J. H. The Fourteenth Amendment, the Negro, and the spirit of the times. -- In Journal of Negro History. -- Vol. 45, 1960 Jan. (Box 141, Folder 48)
    - Abraham Lincoln auxiliary. -- Independent Klan of America., 1920s (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Abramowitz, Jack. The Negro in the Agrarian Revolt. -- In Agricultural History. -- Vol. 24, 1950 Apr. (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Abrams, Richard M. A paradox of Progressivism: Massachusetts on the eve of insurgency. -- In Political Science Quarterly. -- Vol. 75, 1960 Sept. (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - Adams, George R. Black voices in black militant poetry. -- In TMS., 1969 (Box 142, Folder 4)
    - Adler, Les K. and Thomas Paterson. Red fascism: the merger of Nazi Germany and Soviet Russia in the American Image of Totalitarianism, 1930s-1950s. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 75, no. 4, 1970 Apr. (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Africa. -- In The Sun [Baltimore, MD]., 1969 Apr. 22 (Box 142, Folder 6)
    - Aldrich, Mark. Progressive economists and scientific racism: Walter Wilcox and black Americans, 1895-1910. -- In Phylon. -- Vol. XL, no. 1, 1979 Spring (Box 142, Folder 7)
    - Alexander, Charles C. Prophet of American racism: Madison Grant, and the Nordic myth. -- In Phylon., 1962 Spring (Box 142, Folder 8)
    - Americans all, immigrants all., n.d. (Box 142, Folder 9)
    - Angoff, Charles. Oswald Garrison Villard and the Nation: a memoir. -- In Antioch Review. -- Vol. 23, 1963 Summer (Box 142, Folder 10)
    - Asada, Sadao. Japan's 'Special Interests' and the Washington Conference, 1921-22. -- In AHR., 1961 Oct. (Box 142, Folder 11)
    - Baldwin, C. B. Politics for progress, 1954., n.d. (Box 142, Folder 12)
    - Barnard, Harry. In defense of T. R. -- In The Nation., 1958 Apr. 19 (Box 142, Folder 13)
    - Baron, Harold. Anti-imperialism and the Democrats. -- In Science & Society. -- Vol. 21, no. 3, 1957 Summer (Box 142, Folder 14)
    - Bates, J. Leonard. Fulfilling American democracy: the Conservation Movement, 1907-1921. -- In MHVR. -- Vol. 44, 1951 June (Box 142, Folder 15)
    - Becker, Joseph M. Twenty-five years of unemployment insurance. -- In Political Science Quarterly. -- Vol. 75, no. 4, 1960 Dec. (Box 142, Folder 16)
    - Bell, Howard. Expressions of Negro militancy in the North, 1840-1860. -- In Journal of Negro History. -- Vol. 45, 1960 (Box 142, Folder 17)
    - Berman, Paul. From A tale of two utopias: the political journey of the generation of 1968. -- p. 78-83, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 18)
    - Bernstein, Samuel. American labor in the long depression, 1873-1878. -- In Science & Society, 1956 Winter (Box 142, Folder 19)
    - Berthoff, Rowland. The American social order: a conservative hypothesis. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 65, no. 3, 1960 Apr. (Box 142, Folder 20)
    - Billington, Ray Allen. Government & the arts: the WPA experience. -- In American Quarterly. -- Vol. 13, no. 4, 1961 Dec. (Box 142, Folder 21)
    - Billotta, James D. Critique of Styron's Confession of Nat Turner. -- In Negro History Bulletin. -- Vol. 38, no. 1, 1975 Dec. - Jan. (Box 142, Folder 22)
    - Black America: a special issue. -- In The Nation, 1978 Dec. 16 (Box 142, Folder 23)
    - Blake, Nelson Manfred. Ambassadors at the court of Theodore Roosevelt. -- In Mississippi Valley Historical Review. -- Vol. 42, 1955 Sept. (Box 142, Folder 24)
    - Bolkhovitinov, Nikolai. The Cliometricians & slavery in the U.S. -- In Social Science. -- Vol. 7, no. 4, 1976 (Box 142, Folder 25)
    - Bolkhovitinov, Nikolai. Some problems of the historiography of the American Revolution of the 18th century, 1974 (Box 142, Folder 26)
    - Bolkhovitinov, Nikolai and S.I. Divilkovski. Russian diplomacy and the Anglo-American War of 1812-1814. -- In Soviet Studies in History, 1962 Fall (Box 142, Folder 27)
    - Bornet, Vaughn Davis. The Communisty Party in the presidential election of 1928. -- In Western Political Quarterly. -- Vol. 11, 1958 Sept. (Box 142, Folder 28)
    - Bowman, Albert. Review of Entangling alliance: politics & diplomacy under George Washington. -- In Political Science Quarterly. -- Vol. 73, no. 4, 1958 Dec. (Box 142, Folder 29)
    - Boyd, Herlo. Ollie Harrington: in memoriam. -- In Black Scholar. -- Vol. 25, no. 4, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 30)
    - Brand, George. Toward a history of the New Deal. -- In Monthly Review, 1960 May (Box 142, Folder 31)
    - Bremner, Robert H. The big flat: a history of a New York Tenement house. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 64, no. 1, 1958 Oct. (Box 142, Folder 32)
    - Brewer, William. Review of The cotton regency, northern merchants, & Reconstruction, 1865-1880. -- In Journal of Negro History. -- Vol. 45, 1960 Jan. (Box 142, Folder 33)
    - Buhle, Paul. The also serve who tell the tale: book review. -- In The Nation, 1976 Apr. 3 (Box 142, Folder 34)
    - Buhle, Paul and Robin D.G. Kelley. Allies at a different sort: Jews & Blacks in the American Left, n.d., tms (34 p.) (Box 142, Folder 35)
    - Burks, David D. The United States and the Geneva Protocol of 1924: a new holy alliance? -- p. 891-905, 1959 (Box 142, Folder 36)
    - Burnham, John Chynoweth. Psychiatry, psychology, and the Progressive Movement. -- In American Quarterly. -- Vol. 12, 1960 Winter (Box 142, Folder 37)
    - Burtner, David. From Making peace with the 60s. -- p. 134-137, 1996 (Box 142, Folder 38)
    - Butow, Robert J.C. The Hull-Nomura conversations: a fundamental misconception. -- In American Historical Review. -- Vol. 65, 1960 July (Box 142, Folder 39)
    - Campbell, Charles S. The dismissal of Lord Sackville. -- Mississippi Valley Historical Review. -- Vol. 44, 1958 Mar. (Box 142, Folder 40)
    - Carter, Everett. Cultural history written with lightening: the significance of The birth of a nation. -- In American Quarterly, 1960 Fall (Box 142, Folder 41)
    - Carter, Harvey. The far-West in American history. -- In Service Center for Teachers of History. -- No. 26, 1960 (Box 142, Folder 42)
    - Clark, Thomas D. The great visitation to American democracy. -- In Mississippi Valley Historical Review. -- Vol. 44, 1957 June (Box 142, Folder 43)
    - Clements, Roger. British investment and American legislative restrictions in the Trans-Mississippi West, 1880-1900. -- In Mississippi Valley Historical Review. -- Vol. 42, 1955 Sept. (Box 142, Folder 44)
    - Clubb, O. Edmund. Formosa and the offshore islands in American policy, 1950-1955. -- In Political Science Quarterly. -- Vol. 74, no. 4, 1959 Dec. (Box 142, Folder 45)
    - Cohen, Morton N. Mark Twain and the Phillippines: containing an unpublished letter. -- In Journal of the Central Mississippi Valley American Studies Association. -- Vol. 1, no. 2, 1960 Fall (Box 142, Folder 46)
    - Cohen, Naomi. Ambassador Straus in Turkey, 1909-1910: a note on Dollar Diplomacy. -- In Mississippi Valley Historical Review. -- Vol. 45, 1959 Mar. (Box 142, Folder 47)
    - Cohen, Sol. The industrial education movement, 1906-1917. -- In American Quarterly. -- Vol. 20, 1968 Spring (Box 142, Folder 48)
    - Cole, G.D.H. What is wrong with the Soviet Union. -- In New World Review, 1957 Nov. (Box 142, Folder 49)
    - Cole, Wayne S. American entry into World War II: a historigraphical appraisal. -- In Mississippi Valley Historical Review. -- Vol. 43, 1957 Mar. (Box 142, Folder 50)
    - Cole, Wayne S. Senator Pittman & American neutrality policies, 1933-1940. -- In Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1960 Mar. (Box 142, Folder 51)
    - The colour bar in Great Britain. -- In The Spectator, 1931 Feb. 14 (Box 142, Folder 52)
    - Congressional Record, 1930 July 18 (Box 142, Folder 53)
    - Cook, Fred J. Galindez: the riddle of the mystery. -- In The Nation, 1957 Aug. 3 (Box 142, Folder 54)
    - Cuban, Larry. A strategy for racial peace: Negro leadership in Cleveland, 1900-1919. -- In Phylon. -- Vol. 28, 1967 Fall (Box 142, Folder 55)
    - Cunningham, Frank. Pluralism and class struggle. -- In Science & Society. -- Vol. 39, no. 4, 1975 - 1976 Winter (Box 142, Folder 56)
    - Cunningham, Raymond. The Emmanuel movement: a variety of American religious experience. -- In American Quarterly. -- Vol. 14, no. 1, 1962 Spring (Box 142, Folder 57)
    - Davis, David Brion. The age of federalism: [review]. -- In New York Review of Books. -- Vol. 41, no. 9, 1994 May 12, 4 p. (Box 142, Folder 58)
    - Davis, David Brion. Terror in Mississippi. -- In New York Review of Books. -- Vol. 40, no. 18, 1993 Nov. 4, 6 p. (Box 142, Folder 59)
    - Davis, John A. Black Americans and United States policy toward Africa. -- In Journal of International Affairs. -- Vol. 23, no. 2, 1969 (Box 142, Folder 60)
    - John W. Davis, father of the Un-American Activities Committees & their progeny, n.d. (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Decker, Leslie E. The railroads and the Land Office: administrative policy and the Land patent controversy, 1864-1896. -- In Mississippi Valley Historical Review, 1960 Mar. (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Degler, Carl. Review of Brass Knuckle Crusade: the great-know-nothing crusade, 1820-1860. -- In The Nation, 1960 Aug. 20 (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Degler, Carl N. Slavery and the genesis of American race prejudice. -- In Comparative Studies in Society & History (Hague). -- Vol. 2, no. 1, 1959 Oct. (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Della Chiesa, Vittorio. Review of Johnson's The battle cry of freedom. -- In Science & Society, 1956 Winter (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Dennis, Peggy. Re: the New Republic article, June 23, 1979 implicating Eugene Dennis as a pivot to an alleged Julius Rosenberg 'confession', 1979 July, tms (6 p.) (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Detweiler, Philip. Congressional debate on slavery and the Declaration of Independence, 1819-1821. -- In American Historical Review, 1958 Apr. (Box 143, Folder 7)